ILGWU. Gus Tyler papers, 5780/052
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Series II. Subject files., 1948-1979
  - ILGWU Scholarship Fund, 1962-1969 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    Local scholarship Fund.
  - ILGWU Scholarship Fund, 1959-1963 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    Marvin Rogoff corres.
  - ILGWU Scholarship Fund, 1958-1960 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    Selection Comm. meetings & related corres.
  - ILGWU Scholarship Fund, 1961-1964 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - ILGWU Scholarship Fund, 1965-1969 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - ILGWU Scholarship Fund, 1958-1966 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    Statistical data.
  - ILGWU Training Institute, 1933-1962 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - ILGWU Training Institute, 1963-1964 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - ILGWU Training Institute [folder 1 of 2], 1961 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    June 1961. Central States & Midwest Region Insts., University of Wisconsin.
  - ILGWU Training Institute [folder 1 of 2], 1961 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - ILGWU Training Institute, 1957-1962 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    Spanish projects.
  - ILGWU Training Institute, 1952 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    Student records.
  - ILGWU Training Institute, 1954 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - ILGWU Training Institute, 1959 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - ILGWU Training Institute (n.d.) (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - ILGWU Training Institute, Printed Material, 1957-1959 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    Incl. G.T. publications: "Building Tomorrow's Labor Leadership", 1957; "ILGWU's Training Institute", 1959.
  - The International League for the Rights of Man, 1962-1963 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Irish University Press, 1969 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    Corres. w. Michael Glazier re creating library w. theme on theme on the American worker.
  - Israel, 1971-1973 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Jackson, Senator Henry (Scoop), for President, 1976 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Japan Society, Inc., 1973 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Jewish Daily Forward, 1971-1976 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    Incl. article "Der Proletarishker Maggid", on 75th anniversary of the Forward.
  - Jewish Labor Committee, 1959-1960 (Box 18, Folder 9)
    Incl. Herbert Hill article "Labor Unions & the Negro", December 1959. Corres. & printed material on relations between Blacks & Jews.
  - Jewish Labor Committee, 1961-1963 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Job Applications, 1973-1975 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Job Applications, 1977 (Box 18, Folder 12)
    June 1977.
  - Job Applications, 1977 (Box 18, Folder 13)
    July-December 1977.
  - Judy Bond Strike, 1962 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Kelman, Mark, 1970-1971 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Kennedy, John F., 1960 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    December 1960. Letter thanking G.T. for his assistance in Presidential campaign.
  - Labor Committee for Political Action in New York State, 1975-1976 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Labor Theater, 1973 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Lawrence Manufacturing Company (Lawrenceville, Va.), 1959-1960 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    Letters from Joseph Shane & printed material on campaign to organize firm.
  - Liberal Party, 1971-1974 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Lipsig, James, 1971-1974 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Local 23-25, 1973 (Box 19, Folder 9)
    Jay Mazur paper presented at ITF/BRAC Asian Regional Trade Union Educators' Conference, Penang, Malaysia.
  - Local 32, 1958-1959 (Box 19, Folder 10)
    Incl. G.T. articles on Abe Snyder (bio. sketches
  - Local 91 Film Script - "Welcome to Local 91". (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Lovestone, Jay, 1969-1972 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - March on Washington - "Rally for Jobs", 1975 (Box 19, Folder 13)
    Sponsored by the Industrial Union Department, AFL-CIO.
  - Meany, George, Labor Studies Center, 1976-1977 (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Minimum Wage, 1966-1971 (Box 19, Folder 15)
    Incl. testimony & union resolutions for Puerto Rico minimum wage, 1971.
  - Morrisett, Lloyd N. (res. the John and Mary R. Markele Foundation), 1973-1974 (Box 19, Folder 16)
    Incl. G.T. paper "Guidelines for an Inquiry Into TV's Role in the Electoral Process", 1973.
  - Mosler, Sheila, 1972 (Box 19, Folder 17)
    Incl. G.T. paper "For a Metroscopic View of New York".
  - Motion Picture Association of America, 1975 (Box 19, Folder 18)
    Corres. w. Jack Valenti.
  - Moynihan, Daniel, Patrick, Senate Campaign [folder 1 of 2], 1976 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Moynihan, Daniel, Patrick, Senate Campaign [folder 2 of 2], 1976 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Museum of the City of New York, 1970-1974 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - National Academy of Science Commission on International Affairs, 1977 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    Incl. G.T. paper "The Threat to American Manufacture".
  - National Advisory Committee of the Martin Luther King Jr. Institute and School of Social Change, 1969 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - National-American Wholesale Grocers' Association, 1974 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    Incl. G.T. paper "The Labor Climate", September.
  - National Assembly for Social Policy and Development, 1967-1973 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - National Association for the Advancement of Colored People, 1965-1976 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - National Broadcasting Corporation, 1959-1971 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - National Center for Education in Politics (formerly Citizens Clearing House), 1961 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - National Center for Education in Politics, 1962 (Box 20, Folder 11)
    February-June 1962.
  - National Center for Education in Politics, 1962-1963 (Box 20, Folder 12)
    July 1962-1963.
  - National Coalition for Lower Tuition in Higher Education, 1975 (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - National Commission on Reform of Federal Criminal Laws, 1966-1969 (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - National (leadership) and Legislative Conference, ILGWU, 1960 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - National and Legislative Conference, ILGWU. [folder 1 of 2], 1976 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    January 1976.
  - National and Legislative Conference, ILGWU. [folder 2 of 2], 1976 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - National Leadership Legislative Conferences, ILGWU, 1977-1978 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - National Municipal League, 1957-1962 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - National Recreation Association, 1960-1963 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - National Service Corps, 1962 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - National Urban League, Inc., 1962-1963 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - New Left (Box 21, Folder 9)
    Articles from various sources analyzing the "New Left".
  - New Republic, 1970-1975 (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - New Rochelle College, 1972-1973 (Box 21, Folder 11)
    Incl. corres. & material on teaching assignments.
  - New School - G.T. Lecture Series, 1974 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - New York City and State Governments, 1970-1976 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    General matters.
  - New York City. Commercial Rent, 1969-1970 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    Corres. re rent increases and its effect on N.Y.C. apparel industry.
  - New York City. Consumer Affairs Department, 1974 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - New York City. Department for the Aging, 1974 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - New York City. Mayor's Office of Apparel Industry Planning and Development, 1970-1971 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - OPUS 70-70. Art exposition on Union's 70th anniversary. (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Organizing, ILGWU, 1976-1977 (Box 22, Folder 8)
    Incl. reports from affiliates, applications, ILGWU school for organizers.
  - Organizers Seminar, 1977 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Organizers, School for (ILGWU), 1976 (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - The Philadelphia Story - ILGWU, 1970 (Box 22, Folder 11)
    Prepared by Sidney Rothstein.
  - Politics, 1968-1973 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Rainbow productions, 1962 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    Re Organized Crime in America, agreement. G.T. book.
  - Randolph, A. Philip, Institute, 1968-1972 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    1975-78. Incl. corres. w. Maida Springer Kemp, 1968-72.
  - Reapportionment in Assembly, Senate and Congressional Districts, 1968-1972 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    Incl. David I. Wells' statements.
  - Reassessing American Values, Inc. -A Bicentennial Public Education/ Program, 1974-1975 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Regional Departments. Canada, 1976-1977 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Central States Region, 1961-1962 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    Incl. corres. & reports from Rita Oberbeck on Educational Department activities.
  - Cloak-Out-of-Town Department, 1961-1962 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Regional Departments. Eastern Region, 1973-1977 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Regional Departments. Midwest Area, 1961-1976 (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Regional Departments. New England Area, 1975-1977 (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Regional Departments. New York State District, 1977 (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - Regional Departments. Ohio-Kentucky, 1960-1977 (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - Regional Departments. Philadelphia, 1961-1962 (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - Regional Departments. Puerto Rico, 1961-1976 (Box 23, Folder 16)
  - Regional Departments. Southeast, 1976-1977 (Box 23, Folder 17)
  - Regional Departments. Upper South Region, 1961-1977 (Box 23, Folder 18)
  - Reports to Convention (Education Department), 1967-1975 (Box 23, Folder 19)
  - Research Department, 1948-1955 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Roche, John P. (Course), 1973 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Royer, John R., 1962 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Seventieth Anniversary. Special events, exhibits, programs. (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Seventy-Fifth Anniversary. [folder 1 of 3] (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Seventy-Fifth Anniversary. [folder 2 of 3] (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Seventy-Fifth Anniversary. [folder 3 of 3] (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - McGraw Hill Exhibit. (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Seventy-Fifth Anniversary. Show at Unity House. (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Seventy-Fifth Anniversary. Tri-section mural, newspapers and articles. (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Shulman, Beverly, 1973-1977 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Smithsonian Institution, 1972 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    Corres. re union's participation in American Folklore Festival, Washington, D.C., Incl. articles "Hand Made" & "Hand" by Leon Stein.
  - Staff meetings, 1961 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Student Loan Program, 1968-1971 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Students for a Democratic Society (National Student Association, 1961 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - A Study of Voter Attitudes Toward Unions and Unionization in Missouri and Arkansas, 1977 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    November 1977. Prepared for the ILGWU by Yankelovich, Skelly and White, Inc.
  - Stulberg, Louis, 1960-1974 (Box 25, Folder 7)
    Super Market Institute, Inc., 1974. Incl. G.T. presentation at SMI Europe conference.
  - Supermarket Institute (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Taxation with Representation (A Public Interest Taxpayers' Lobby), 1973-1976 (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - The Twentieth Century Fund, 1972 (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Union Health Center, 1963-1973 (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Union Label Department, 1960-1963 (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - Unions in Action, labor exhibit in Caracas, Venezuela, 1980 (Box 25, Folder 13)
    May 1980.
  - United Church for World Ministries, 1974-1975 (Box 25, Folder 14)
  - United States Youth Council, 1970-1974 (Box 25, Folder 15)
  - Unity House, 1967-1974 (Box 25, Folder 16)
  - University (Classes), 1976-1977 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Visitors to ILGWU, 1958-1963 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Waldinger, Roger (staff member, Education Department), 1975 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - The Weatherhead Foundation, 1970 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - The Weatherhead Foundation, 1971 (Box 26, Folder 5)
    Corres. re Conference for Economic & Educational Perspectives of the Mexican-American.
  - The Weatherhead Foundation, 1972 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    Corres. (cont'd) on Mexican-American Conference, August 26-30.
  - The Weatherhead Foundation, 1972-1975 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Western States Region, 1971-1973 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - White House Conference on Aging, 1970-1971 (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Women's Campaign Fund, 1974 (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Woodrow Wilson National Fellowship Foundation, 1974 (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - Workmen's Circle, 1970-1974 (Box 26, Folder 12)
- Series III. Articles., 1950-1980
  - American Labor, A Growing and Changing Movement. United States Information Service, 1968 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    May 1968.
  - American Labour in Politics. American Labour, 1968 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    November 1968.
  - "American Politics: How They Work and How You Can Work Them." (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Assignment '68: A Discussion on The Role of the Labor Press. Int'l. Labor Press Assoc. AFL-CIO, 1968 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - The Battle Against Political Corruption. From symposium "Needed, 1952 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    Sponsored by the League for Industrial Democracy, Inc.
  - Beyond Equality, Labor and the Radical Republicans, 1862-1872. By David Montgomery. Book review, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Louis D. Brandeis' Way to Jewish Identification. Herzl Institute Bulletin, 1966 (Box 27, Folder 7)
    November 1966. Vol. 3, No. 6.
  - Breaking Party Lines. N.Y. Times letter, 1970 (Box 27, Folder 8)
    September 23, 1970.
  - To Build A Liberal Coalition. ADA World, 1967 (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Building Tomorrow's Labor Leadership, 1957 (Box 27, Folder 10)
    Summer 1957. Reprint from AFL-CIO Industrial Union Department Digest.
  - Can Anyone Run A City. Saturday Review, 1969 (Box 27, Folder 11)
    November 8, 1969.
  - Career Education and Society's Imperatives, 1973 (Box 27, Folder 12)
    April 1973. Published by Northwest Regional Educational Laboratory, Portland Oregon, under contract with U.S. Office of Education.
  - The Case for Hubert Humphrey, (Humphrey the Vital Center), 1968 (Box 27, Folder 13)
    June 1968. The Progressive.
  - The Central Issues of Our Time: How They Affect Labor and The Community, 1969 (Box 27, Folder 14)
    May 1969. Speech delivered at the Fourteenth Annual AFL-CIO National Conference on Community Service.
  - Change articles. "Everybody's Core Curriculum", 1970 (Box 27, Folder 15)
    May- June 1970.
  - Change articles. "The Faculty Joins the Proletariat", 1971-1972 (Box 27, Folder 16)
    Winter 1971/72.
  - Change articles. "The University and the Labor Union: Educating the Proletariat", 1979 (Box 27, Folder 17)
    February 1979.
  - "The Changing Face of Labor". Outline, 1967 (Box 27, Folder 18)
  - "Classrooms Born of the Class Struggle: An Overview", 1961 (Box 27, Folder 19)
    February 1961. 3pp.
  - Clothing Industry is A Bit Threadbare. Interview by Eliot Janeway, 1971 (Box 27, Folder 20)
    November 1971.
  - Combating Organized Crime The Annals (of the Academy of Political and Social Science), 1963 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    May 1963. Volume 347.
  - Commentary and Symposium, 1965-1973 (Box 28, Folder 2)
    "S.J. Res. No. 2 The Quiet Counter-Revolution", June 1965; Reply to Alexander M. Bickel's article "Is Electoral Reform the Answer?", December 1968; Reply to Pfaff article, February 1968; Nixon, The Great Society and the Future of Social Policy, May 1973; Commentary. "New Deal vs. Old Deal", 1973. Includes correspondence.
  - Symposium. What is a Liberal - Who is a Conservative?, 1976 (Box 28, Folder 3)
    September 1976. Includes correspondence.
  - Court Versus Legislature, 1962 (Box 28, Folder 4)
    Reprint from Symposium on The Electoral Process Part II, published as the Summer 1962 issue of Law and Contemporary Problems, Duke University School of Law.
  - The Crime Corporation. Current Perspectives on Criminal Behavior, 1978 (Box 28, Folder 5)
    Original essays edited by Abraham S. Blumberg.
  - The Criminal and The Community. Current History, 1967 (Box 28, Folder 6)
    August 1967.
  - Dirty Politics, By Bruce L. Felknor. Book review, 1966 (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Dissent, 1961-1971 (Box 28, Folder 8)
    Marginal Industries, Low Wages, and High Risks, 1961; Generation Gap or Gap Within a Generation, April 1971. Includes correspondence.
  - Dissent, 1972-1979 (Box 28, Folder 9)
    White Workers/ Blue Mood, 1972; Mythologies of a Simon-Pure Conservative, Spring 1979. Includes correspondence.
  - The White Worker, 1971 (Box 28, Folder 10)
    Includes correspondence.
  - Dissent. The Friedman Inventions, 1980 (Box 28, Folder 11)
    Summer 1980. Includes correspondence.
  - El Gremialismo en La Vida Politica de Estados Unidos, por Gus Tyler, 1968 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - The Federationist, 1959-1966 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    "The ILGWU's Training Institute", November 1959; "The 1962 Elections", February 1962; "Conservative fide in the Elections", October 1962; "The New Challenge to Liberalism", November 1963; "Goldwater...Front Man for Counter Revolution", October 1964; "Labor's New Horizons", September 1966.
  - The Federationist, 1968-1972 (Box 29, Folder 3)
    "The Politics of '68", March 1968; "The Future of the Liberal Coalition", January 1969; "Labor in the 1970's: A New Era", January 1970; "A New Gerrymander Threat", February 1971 (w. David Wells); "Multinationals: A Global Menace", July 1972.
  - The Federationist, 1973-1979 (Box 29, Folder 4)
    "A Labor View of the 'New Class;", October 1973; "The Threat of A U.S. Without Factories", April 1976; "Minimum Wage: Still Fighting the War on Poverty", May 1977; "The Dangerous Fallacies of A Balanced-Budget Convention", April 1979; "Labor in the 1980's: A New Challenge", November 1979.
  - Full Employment to Fight Inflation, 1977 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Genesis, Anchor Bible Edition. Book review, 1966 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Herald Tribune articles, 1964 (Box 29, Folder 7)
    "Seventh Avenue is Still The Garment Center", March 1964. "New York: The Fashion City", 1964.
  - The Illusions That Were and The Illusions That Are, New Republic, 1957 (Box 29, Folder 8)
    November 4, 1957.
  - Increasing Employment Opportunities for Youth, 1974 (Box 29, Folder 9)
    July 1974. Paper submitted to Department of Health, Education and Welfare, National Institute of Education. 77 pp..
  - The International Role of American Labor", 1973 (Box 29, Folder 10)
    October 1973 Jewish Frontier.
  - The Jewish Labor Movement, Education Synopsis, 1966 (Box 29, Folder 11)
    Vol. II No, 2, pp. 9-19.
  - Labor Goes to Arden House (ILGWU sponsors pioneer staff training program), 1960 (Box 30, Folder 1a)
    July 1960. Reprint Industrial Bulletin, State of New York, Department of Labor.
  - Labor in The Metropolis, Manuscript (Box 30, Folder 1b)
    236pp.
  - Labor Today (3 parts), 1972 (Box 30, Folder 2)
    May 1972. North American Newspaper Alliance.
  - Labor's 14B Defeat Price of Principle, Liberal Party News, 1966 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Labor's Multinational Pains, Foreign Policy, 1973 (Box 30, Folder 4)
    Fall 1973.
  - Labor's Public Responsibility in Public Affairs, 16pp., n.d. (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - A Legislative Campaign lor A Federal Minimum Wage, 1955 (Box 30, Folder 6)
    Henry Holt & Company, 1959.
  - Liberal News. "Some Current Myths About Labor", 1963 (Box 31, Folder 1)
    February 1963; "Liberal Coalition", October 1963; Article for Liberal News, February 1964; "Do-nothing Legislature", April-May 1964.
  - Limits of Corporate Responsibility, 1971 (Box 31, Folder 2)
    September 1971, 24pp. Conference on corporations, Santa Barbara.
  - Lindsay: The Last Puritan?, 1969 (Box 31, Folder 3)
    November 1969. Book review of A Political Life: The Education of John V. Lindsay By Nat Hentoff. 7pp.
  - Georqe Meany, The Making of A Freedom Fighter, 1979 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Middle America's Share of Pie Remains In The Sky (The Seething Silent Majority), 1970 (Box 31, Folder 5)
    Washington Post, February 1970.
  - Midstream. "The Legacy of the Jewish Labor Movement", 1965 (Box 31, Folder 6)
    March 1965; "The Jewish Labor Movement: A Living Legacy", 1963, publication of the Nathan C. Chanin Cultural Foundation; "Labor's New Era", October 1966; "Negro-Jewish Relations in America", October 19 "Duel in the A.D.A. (Johnson and the Intellectuals)".
  - The Modern Maladies of Maldistribution, 1973 (Box 31, Folder 7)
    August 1973. Paper for People's Policy Center.
  - Multinationals and the Myth of Comparative Advantage, 1978 (Box 31, Folder 8)
    American Labor in a Changing world Economy, Carnegie Endowment for International Peace, edited by Ward Morehouse.
  - New Leader, 1964-1967 (Box 31, Folder 9)
    "Congress and the Succession", March 1964; "Dangers of a Professional Army", April 1967 (w. David Wells) "The Liberal Crisis", October 1967; "The Liberal Crisis-II: to Exchange", Joseph L. Raugh, Sr. - Gus Tyler, November 1967
  - New Leader, 1968 (Box 31, Folder 10)
    "How A Free People Conduct A Long War", January 1968; "After Hew Hampshire", March 1968; "A Plea for Sanity", June 1968; "The Liberal Crisis - Now", October 1968? "A Liberal Agenda", November 1968.
  - New Leader, 1969 (Box 31, Folder 11)
    "Agenda For the Democrats" 14 articles 1969. "1970: Year of Decision", "Puncturing the Liberal Illusion", "Uncovering The Rules", "Missies and Money", "The Revolt of Mr. Middle", "Insurrection of the In-Betweens", "Coalitions Old and New", "Coalition of the Comfortable", "The Academic Question", "A Tale of Three Cities: 1969", "The Working Class Rediscovered", "Playing Poor Politics", "Looking To The Future", "Saving the Party" (missing).
  - New Leader, 1970-1972 (Box 32, Folder 1)
    "Moving Beyond the New Deal", November 1970; "Nixon Vs. The Zeitgeist", February 1972; "Muskie Vs. Nixon: An Early Reading", March 1972; "The Voters Tails Back", June 1972; "(McGovern at Delphi)", June 1972; "Advice To A Candidate", July 1972; "The Nixon Formula", October 1972; "Four More Years - Or Decades?", November 1972.
  - New Leader, 1973 (Box 32, Folder 2)
    "The Politics of Pat Moynihan", April 1973; "Reply: The Politics of The 'Nonpolitical'", May 1973
  - New Leader, 1973-1976 (Box 32, Folder 3)
    "The Uses of History", December 1973; "John Roche: The Loneliness of A Social-Democrat", G.T. review of book Sentenced To Life, by John P. Roche; Democrats Head to A Brokered Convention, February 1976? "The Democrats Double Irony", March 1976; "Third-Party Capers", April 1976,
  - New Leader, 1976 (Box 32, Folder 4)
    "The Rise of Jimmy Carter, April 1976? "The Decline of the Northwest", June 1976; "Carter: Passing Episode Or Start of A New era", July 1976; The Spirit of '76", August 1976,
  - New Leader, 1976-1978 (Box 32, Folder 5)
    "The Economy As A Political Issue", September 1976; "The Year of Realignment", September 1975; "Fooled By The Phillips Curve", October 1976; "The Politics of Dissolution", October 1976; "The Other Economy: America's Working Poor"*, May 1978; "The Carter Mandate" November 197
  - A New Philosophy For Labor, The Fund for The Republic, 1959 (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - New Republic, 1954-1979 (Box 33, Folder 1)
    "The House of Un-Representatives", 1954? "Hidden Democratic Gains", January 1955? "Camel Bites Dachshund" (w. David Wells), November 1961; "Fresh Breezes in The Labor Movement", May 1%. "President Dumping", letter, November 1967; Translation of James Reston October 1961 article brought-up-to-date, "Washington - on (Johnson's) Disenchanted Intellectuals", 1964; "Walter Reuther", May 1979; Letter, October 1970.
  - New York Magazine, 1968-1971 (Box 33, Folder 2)
    "Eight Million Pieces of The Action", c. 1968-69; Against The Evidence - The Becker-Rosenthal Affair, by Andy Logan, G.T. book review, June 1970; "The Beginning Of The End Of The State's Minor Parties?", May 1971.
  - New York Magazine. "Looking Back -At The 'Forward'", 1972 (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - New York Magazine. "Through The Needle's Eyes 75 Years of New York". (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Newsday articles, 1968-1973 (Box 33, Folder 5)
    "A Liberal's Case for Humphrey", July 1968; "0ur Neglected Children", August 1972? "Who Is Turning Us Into A Colony?", June 1973.
  - The Pattern of Garments, 1960 (Box 33, Folder 6)
    14pp..
  - The Political Imperative; The Corporate Character of Unions, by G.T., 1968 (Box 33, Folder 7)
    book distribution.
  - The Presidency and Labor, 1950 (Box 33, Folder 8)
    Reprint, The Annals of the American Academy of Political and Social Science, Philadelphia, Vol. 397, September 1950, pp. 52-91.
  - Progress and Retrogression, 1969 (Box 33, Folder 9)
    Government and the Democratic Process, Symposium by American and Israeli experts. Edited by Judd L. Teller, American Histadrut Cultural Exchange Program.